<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Sahil's Blog - misc</title><link href="https://sahil-sagwekar2652.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://sahil-sagwekar2652.github.io/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://sahil-sagwekar2652.github.io/</id><updated>2023-08-28T12:54:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Practical Productivity Hacks</title><link href="https://sahil-sagwekar2652.github.io/practical-productivity-hacks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-28T12:54:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-08-28T12:54:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Sahil Sagwekar</name></author><id>tag:sahil-sagwekar2652.github.io,2023-08-28:/practical-productivity-hacks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In today's age, the ability to focus and pay attention to one thing is diminishing amongst the younger generation. A large part of the cause can be attributed to social media. Facebook is more of a mass social manipulation experiment than it is a tech company. But we shall not …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In today's age, the ability to focus and pay attention to one thing is diminishing amongst the younger generation. A large part of the cause can be attributed to social media. Facebook is more of a mass social manipulation experiment than it is a tech company. But we shall not go on that tangent. Here, I will share some hacks which are popular and also some which I have devised on my own which will help you increase your productivity and get things done faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let's dive in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="heading-1-breaking-the-instant-gratification-cycle"&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Breaking the Instant Gratification Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/tLZhFRLj6nY"&gt;&lt;img alt class="image--center mx-auto" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1563986768494-4dee2763ff3f?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;amp;ixid=M3wxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8fA%3D%3D&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=2070&amp;amp;q=80"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="heading-httpsemojipediaorgmobile-phonecounter-social-media-addiction"&gt;&lt;a href="https://emojipedia.org/mobile-phone"&gt;📱&lt;/a&gt;Counter Social Media Addiction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever find yourself lost in the quicksand of social media's dopamine rush? It's a universal struggle. From those mesmerizing YouTube shorts to the captivating world of Instagram reels, it's all about those lightning-fast dopamine hits. But here's the savvy twist: use social media with intent. If it's not adding real value, recalibrate. Instagram's tricky waters can leave you high and dry unless you're a creator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube is unavoidable due to it being the largest video search engine. But YouTube courses are free only if you are willing to pay attention. &lt;a href="https://unhook.app/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unhook.app&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a great browser extension that hides the YouTube recommendations feed and the watch next column.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://x.com"&gt;X.com&lt;/a&gt; is in my opinion the best social media for developers, where 'Learning in Public' takes center stage. You will find a lot of people supporting you on your journey and also reaching out to you for opportunities. Just remember, time is precious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="heading-httpswwwgooglecomurlsatandamprctjandampqandampesrcsandampsourcewebandampcdandampved2ahukewip2sz3xv-aaxwsdpuhhcy1ajiqfnoecb8qaqandampurlhttps3a2f2femojipediaorg2fglobe-with-meridiansandampusgaovvaw38sx0alarvhrwur8fqa09sandampopi89978449-plus-pro-tip"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwip2sz3xv-AAxWsdPUHHcY1AJIQFnoECB8QAQ&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Femojipedia.org%2Fglobe-with-meridians&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw38sx0AlaRVHRWUR8Fqa09s&amp;amp;opi=89978449"&gt;🌐&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Plus, Pro Tip:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate the content maze with RSS feeds. Stay at the forefront with news, blogs, and even YouTube channels. Yes, Hashnode blogs too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game-changer? Setting up a desktop RSS feed reader. &lt;strong&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/strong&gt; email client takes the lead, especially for our Linux aficionados. I use it too. Here is a video on how to set up RSS feeds on Thunderbird -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/rF3Yrguwy0M?si=8FPhCaGIOVhrRk28"&gt;Setup RSS on Thunderbird&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://authory.com/blog/create-a-youtube-rss-feed-with-vastly-increased-limits"&gt;Find RSS links for YouTube channels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="heading-2-the-power-of-putting-pen-to-paper"&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;The Power of Putting Pen to Paper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/6qThS1x6P6A"&gt;&lt;img alt class="image--center mx-auto" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1572273869941-45732d6f581c?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;amp;ixid=M3wxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8fA%3D%3D&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=2069&amp;amp;q=80"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The oldest trick, timeless and unfailingly effective put pen to paper. Writing down your goals means writing them down on a piece of paper, preferably a diary or journal, the magic is in the tactile connection. Although this in itself is a good practice; what's better is maintaining a journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daily journaling ideally consists of writing down goals for the day and then writing a summary of what you achieved and what the next set of goals are at the end of the day. This journal, a mirror to your journey, nurtures accountability and tangible growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="heading-3-embrace-full-screen-mode"&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Embrace Full-Screen Mode&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have all been guilty of tab-hopping. I often find myself switching through tabs and windows with my fingers constantly on Ctrl+Tab and Alt+Tab. If you are someone like me who gets distracted easily by other open tabs and applications, you need to start using full-screen mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-tasking is an illusion.&lt;/strong&gt; The human brain works similarly to a single-core CPU in this aspect. You cannot handle two processes at the same time, you can only switch between tasks. For us humans, switching between tasks can be very counter-productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt class="image--center mx-auto" src="https://cdn.hashnode.com/res/hashnode/image/upload/v1693233003752/04bc3bfd-473e-422d-804a-16ea75e7971c.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So whether you're deep into coding or surfing the web, embrace full-screen bliss. It's my go-to secret to obliterate visual clutter. I'm using full-screen even as I write this blog ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="heading-4-action-beats-theory-just-write-code"&gt;4. 👨💻&lt;strong&gt;Action Beats Theory:&lt;/strong&gt; Just Write Code&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {.embed-wrapper}
::: {.embed-loading}
::: {.loadingRow}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {.loadingRow}
:::
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/QMbx0dTWJIQ?si=x3YmLPz5T2sJxWhN"&gt;https://youtu.be/QMbx0dTWJIQ?si=x3YmLPz5T2sJxWhN&lt;/a&gt;
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The hardest part about learning to code is writing the actual code.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find ways to force yourself to read less, watch less and write code more. Start working on a project and learn on the go. &lt;strong&gt;Counterintuitive? Absolutely. The truth? The learning journey knows no finish line.&lt;/strong&gt; I was a person who used to think that I needed to master all the technologies before starting a project. But I realized that there is no end to learning.&lt;br&gt;
You will find yourself at the same spot from where you began even after spending weeks 'learning'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Announce that you are working on a project publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participate in hackathons and competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="heading-httpsemojipediaorghigh-voltagea-high-octane-hackathon-delivers-more-knowledge-in-two-days-than-months-of-theoretical-pursuit"&gt;&lt;a href="https://emojipedia.org/high-voltage"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A high-octane hackathon delivers more knowledge in two days than months of theoretical pursuit.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id="heading-let-go-of-any-hesitations-open-your-ide-and-just-start-coding"&gt;Let go of any hesitations, open your IDE and just start coding!&lt;/h4&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Starting your coding journey might not be as hard as you think…</title><link href="https://sahil-sagwekar2652.github.io/starting-your-coding-journey-might-not-be-as-hard-as-you-think.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-31T13:12:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-01-31T13:12:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Sahil Sagwekar</name></author><id>tag:sahil-sagwekar2652.github.io,2023-01-31:/starting-your-coding-journey-might-not-be-as-hard-as-you-think.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You could be anyone, a high-school student going down the online rabbit hole or an adult who is frustrated with his current job and looking to switch careers. If you are looking to start your journey as a programmer, this article will help you get up-to-speed on how to start …&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You could be anyone, a high-school student going down the online rabbit hole or an adult who is frustrated with his current job and looking to switch careers. If you are looking to start your journey as a programmer, this article will help you get up-to-speed on how to start your coding adventure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id="heading-it-is-easy-to-start-programming"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is easy to start programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you dont mind sitting in front of a computer and staring at your code for long hours then programming just might be your thing ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming is just like maths in some ways. The only things you need to start doing mathematics are a pen, a piece of paper and your brain. Likewise, a computer of any form factor (even your smartphone) and your brain are all you need to start coding. There is no need for any swanky new setup. Any computer which runs reasonably smoothly will be enough for you to start coding. Tools like Replit make it easy for newcomers to start without setting up a coding environment. Replit is even available as an app for Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would help if you start with a goal. But even if you dont have a goal you should do your homework and find out which path suits you the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to learn to code is through projects. If you start learning the language you may find it boring on the other hand if you start working on a project and learn the language on-the-go chances are you will find yourself learning a new language and its applications simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What sources you refer to solely depends on your taste but there is one thing you should keep in mind and that is .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id="heading-tutorial-hell"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tutorial hell&lt;/strong&gt; 💀&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel like learning through books is more like your thing then there are plenty of great books to pick from. Even then YouTube is likely to be your first choice to look for content while learning new topics and skills. But remember, while using free services the product is the user. You could find yourself in Tutorial hell, which means you are stuck watching tutorial upon tutorial from the recommendations without learning anything substantial. The YouTube algorithm is made in a way that coaxes you into watching more and more videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, &lt;strong&gt;real learning&lt;/strong&gt; happens when through hands-on projects. Not only do you need a good roadmap, but also an environment where you can learn and apply your skills at the same time. This brings us to the next point .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id="heading-benefits-of-paid-platforms"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits of paid platforms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is totally fine if you choose to use YouTube as your primary source of learning, there are a ton of amazing courses on YouTube which are free. But still, they might feel incomplete. Paid courses on Platforms like Codedamn, Udemy or Coursera have courses that have carefully curated content that is regularly updated. Codedamn even provides you with virtual code playgrounds to practice your skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it is recommended that you try out free content on free platforms before committing to a paid course. There are many domains in programming. Web development, Data Science, AI, Machine learning, Game Development, and Mobile development are some popular domains. You should try and get your hands dirty in at least two different domains to understand which one is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id="heading-do-you-need-to-learn-maths-to-start-coding"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you need to learn Maths to start coding?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a good grasp of maths would never hurt anybody but its not necessary if you are just starting. What you need to learn is the skill of &lt;strong&gt;Logic Building&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Problem Solving&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computers were invented to solve complex problems and do tedious, repetitive tasks for humans. Learning how to use conditions and loops to emulate real-life scenarios and solve real-world problems is a part of Logic Building. These skills can only be attained through practice and more practice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to be a Data Scientist or an AI/ML engineer then mathematics becomes a necessary part of your skill set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id="heading-consistency-is-the-best-virtue-of-a-programmer"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consistency is the best virtue of a programmer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like Honesty is the best policy, Consistency is the best virtue of a programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning to code is difficult. At times you may get stuck on a problem for hours and feel like giving up your coding adventure altogether. It happens to all of us. But you must remind yourself that getting stuck and facing problems is all a part of the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It often happens to me that I feel like there is no way to solve an error, but when I look at it again the next day I find out that it was just a silly mistake! It is during times like these you learn the most crucial skill as a programmer which is How to GOOGLE effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you read that correctly, searching for ways to solve an error is a big part of a programmers job. If you come across an error there is an almost 100% chance that someone has already faced and solved that error. The best website for this purpose is StackOverflow. Almost every error you come across will have its solution on StackOverflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="heading-to-conclude-there-is-hardly-anything-you-need-to-start-coding-just-down-a-cup-of-coffee-and-go-for-it"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To conclude, there is hardly anything you need to start coding. Just down a cup of coffee and go for it!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>My contributions @ KWoC 2022</title><link href="https://sahil-sagwekar2652.github.io/my-contributions-kwoc-2022.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-08T20:41:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-01-08T20:41:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Sahil Sagwekar</name></author><id>tag:sahil-sagwekar2652.github.io,2023-01-08:/my-contributions-kwoc-2022.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3 id="heading-ps-i-got-selected-as-a-top-contributorhttpsgithubcomkossiitkgppublic-filesblobmasterkwoc2022-certificatesstudentsahil-sagwekar2652pdf"&gt;P.S. I got selected as a &lt;a href="https://github.com/kossiitkgp/public-files/blob/master/KWoC/2022-Certificates/Student/sahil-sagwekar2652.pdf"&gt;top contributor&lt;/a&gt; 🎉&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="heading-introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a new open-source contributor, participating in the Kharagpur winter of code 2022 event was an incredibly valuable experience for me. I had the opportunity to work on an open-source project and make meaningful contributions to their codebase …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3 id="heading-ps-i-got-selected-as-a-top-contributorhttpsgithubcomkossiitkgppublic-filesblobmasterkwoc2022-certificatesstudentsahil-sagwekar2652pdf"&gt;P.S. I got selected as a &lt;a href="https://github.com/kossiitkgp/public-files/blob/master/KWoC/2022-Certificates/Student/sahil-sagwekar2652.pdf"&gt;top contributor&lt;/a&gt; 🎉&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="heading-introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a new open-source contributor, participating in the Kharagpur winter of code 2022 event was an incredibly valuable experience for me. I had the opportunity to work on an open-source project and make meaningful contributions to their codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="heading-projects-i-worked-on"&gt;Projects I worked on&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sadbro/pydirman"&gt;Pydirman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="heading-list-of-pull-requests-made-by-me"&gt;List of pull requests made by me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sadbro/pydirman/pull/13"&gt;https://github.com/sadbro/pydirman/pull/13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sadbro/pydirman/pull/14"&gt;https://github.com/sadbro/pydirman/pull/14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sadbro/pydirman/pull/15"&gt;https://github.com/sadbro/pydirman/pull/15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sadbro/pydirman/pull/18"&gt;https://github.com/sadbro/pydirman/pull/18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="heading-summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work on Linux and use the command line all the time. This is probably the reason I gravitated towards Pydirman because it is a command-line application for Linux systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first issue I faced with the project was with the installation. The project was initially developed only for Debian Linux. So naturally, my first step was to port the project for Arch Linux (my working distro). I had to replace the bash commands with the package manager for Arch Linux. Features like user input for required packages and optimising the path of the installed files were added and a single setup.py was created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had the project installed I started using the project on a daily basis. Which exposed some bugs and inadequacies. The default text editor used was nano, which is a command line text editor. The command line text editor which is most popular is 'vim'. So I modified the code so that users can use their choice of text editor by specifying it in the '.pydirman.config' configuration file. Another issue concerned with the 'test' command was fixed within this same pull request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next pull request I've updated the README.md to reflect the changes in the project. Also added the support for python debugger, this will enable the user to use the python debugger inside the Pydirman 'test' interface. Added support to execute .pyw python files alongside normal .py files. Finally created an uninstall.py file which removes all the installed files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="heading-future-work"&gt;Future Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a separate terminal emulator with python tkinter to display the 'test' interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding support for the 'u - open USB drive' command for other distros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
(referenced in the Issues tab)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on other projects like: &lt;a href="https://github.com/exitflynn/DeGrasse"&gt;DeGrasse - Python Discord Bot Using NASA Space API's and more&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/proffapt/code-runner"&gt;Code Runner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="heading-learnings"&gt;Learnings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things I learned during my time as a KWoC participant was the importance of effective communication. I also learned the importance of asking for help when needed, as there were always team members and mentors available to support me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also gained valuable experience in project management and time management, as I had to juggle my KWoC commitments with my other responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>